### **SHRUTHI**

Plot 5 flat no A4 Lakshmiganapathi Flats Lakshmi nagar madipakkam chennai 600091

Mobile: +91-9710922339

Email :shrunans@gmail.com

## Summary:

Graduated in Commerce with 4.3 years experience in Finacial Market Operations and Eight months in Anti money Laundering

> Responsible for Nostro Investigations and Compensations.

Wide Knowledge in Foreign Exchange, Money Markets Operations. Encompass Compensations claims from various corporate and interbank Clients.

#### **EXPERIENCE:**

Worked in Scope International, Chennai as Senior Officer- Financial Markets operations from May 2010 to till 2013 December; Global Reconciliation Unit From Jan 2014 till Mar 2015 and as an Analyst in Anti money laundering from Mar 2015 till Oct2015

# **Job Responsibilities:**

- **Investigations** Responsible for Nostro and Compensations.
- Responsibilities analyzing encompass and investigating of the Nostro outstandings.
- > Follow up with the client/remitter for non-receipt of funds Report and settle fail trade on daily basis Maintain MIS on the monthly basis Effective follow up with counter party for claims / compensations Analyze and settle penalties Reconciliation of Nostro charges across all the countries.
- > Won many Icon awards for nostro nil outstanding greater than 30 days as well for nil errors.
- > Project Management Report Preparation.

- > Ensuring the bank performs the financial transactions and maintains the required documents and records in the manner as required by the law
- Analyzing extensive accounting statements to detect any patterns or trends that present illegal activities or frauds
- Preparing weekly/monthly reports on forensic investigation of departmental and organizational accounts

# **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION:**

COURSE	COLLEGE/SCHOOL	UNIVERSITY/BOARD	YEAR	% MARKS
B.Com	M.O.P Vaishnav College For women, Nungambakkam	Madras University	2007-10	70%
HSC	Asan Memorial Matriculation Higher Secondary School, Chennai	Tamil Nadu State Board	2007	87%
SSLC	Asan Memorial Senior Secondary School, Chennai	Central Board	2005	61%

<u>Languages</u> <u>known</u>	<ul> <li>Speak: Tamil, English, Hindi, Gujarathi</li> <li>Read: Tamil, English, Hindi</li> <li>Write: Tamil, English, Hindi</li> </ul>
----------------------------------	--

## **APPLICATIONS USED:**

- > TLM(RECONCILITATION)
- > PSGL(People Soft General Ledger)
- > OPICS GDC (all the deal flow)
- ➤ SC STAR (Messaging system)
- > REUTERUS (Dealers Conversation)
- > CRYSTAL BUSINESS OBJECTS (Comp in reports)
- > CERS (Case log)
- POSEWEB(compensation rates extraction)
- > GDC REPORTS (GL extracts)
- > FILE NET ( Book transfers)
- > ICM( case log maintainance)
- > Detica

Tutions taken for all classes, well versed in English can accommodate for primary classes

Have passion towards teaching hence changing my profile and also will join teachers training asap

Joining date immediate Last designation: Analyst

#### PERSONAL INFORMATION:

NAME : Shruthi L
DATE OF BIRTH : 15/06/1990
SEX : Female

HUSBAND'S NAME : Lakshmi Narayanan V

NATIONALITY : Indian

PLACE: Chennai

DATE: 20-February-2019

(Shruthi)